For the exam, it is important to know what can interfere with both wired and wireless networks.
For wired networks, specifically those using twisted-pair cable, data transmissions can be affected as a result of nearby power cables,
electromagnetic interference, and fluorescent lighting.
For wireless networks, the following can interfere with a wireless signal: heavy machinery, such as elevator shafts; walls, especially for 5 GHz networks;
and anything else that runs on the 2.4 GHz frequency, including items such as microwave ovens and cordless phones.
For both wired and wireless networks, be aware that there could be people trying to intercept data. Important data should be encrypted while being transmitted.
This way, the data is no good to someone who hacks into the network unless that person also has the decryption key.
Also, as with other computer equipment, heavy fluctuations in electricity, such as brownouts, blackouts, spikes, or surges can also cause a problem with data transmissions.
Even lightning can be a problem. Twisted-pair cables are also subject to crosstalk, which occurs when a signal on one pair of wires interferes with another wire or pair of wires.
This is usually a result of a damaged cable, which should be replaced.
For the exam, the most important takeaway from these topics is to understand what can cause interference with data transmissions.